MD SAKHAWAT HOSSAIN



• Home: Lapinniementie 35 A9, 68630, Pietarsaari, Finland

+358417295788 inLinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-sakhawathossain- 375192160

Git hub Project: https://sakhawat2.github.io/Hossain.github.io/

Gender: Male Date of birth: 11/11/1983 Nationality: Bangladeshi

ABOUT ME

An accomplished Team Leader with solid Education and 15 years of experience in designing and managing Customer Service strategies & ensuring timely resolution of customers' queries. Highly responsible Training Manager focused on developing and conducting unique training sessions for a better understanding of machine and processes. Handled team of 11 trainers and conducted various leadership and motivational training materials for organizing company-wide training workshops, Skills. Possess a knack of applying analytical and problem-solving skills to meet clients' varied demands within strict deadlines. Ensures timely completion of identified goals

WORK EXPERIENCE

[08/04/2024 – Current]

Chef

Spartao Oy, Sushibar Pietarsaari Prisma Pietarsaari

City: Pietarsaari | Country: Finland

- · Make and serve Sushi for customer.
- Preparation to make Sushi.
- Preparation for next day.
- · Clean the working area.

[01/05/2017 - 25/12/2023] **Field service manager**

Murata Machinery Bangladesh Ltd. (Sister concern of Murata Machinery Ltd.

Address: Paradise Tower (131h Floor), PloI + 11, Foad # 2, Sector # 03, Uttara, Dhaka, 1230, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Daily oversight of 11-person team. Research and interpret complex data for strategic planning and

business development. Contribute to individual and team projects. Conduct statistical/ financial

analyses; report results and craft recommendations. Administer operational guidelines, standards, and

policies. Compile regular reports detailing sales, customer after visit for maintenance and troubleshooting, inventory control, and management and information systems. Reconcile inventory monthly.

- Troubleshooting, inventory control, and management and information systems. Reconcile inventory monthly.
- Machine installation, Supervising, Commissioning to several customer.
- · Electrical, mechanical and quality trouble shooting.
- Training to customer and new comers (Junior Engineers).
- Assist customer for improvement of product quality and increase efficiency.
- Served 150 customer in Bangladesh and overseas (India, Indonesia, Thailand, Japan)
- Make schedule for 11 staffs to serve 150 customer and co-ordinate.

- Supervised 11 employees including recruitment, training, performance evaluations, and career coaching.
- Served as single point of contact in resolving operations-related customer issues. Achieved 100% customer satisfaction rating on all projects including key clients overseas.
- · Advised senior leadership in operational risks, financials, quality assurance, and audit processes.
- Submit working report and progress report to Japan and all related parson including customer.

[01/03/2005 – 30/04/2017]

Service Engineer

Texcone Engineering. (Authorized agent of Murata Machinery Ltd. Japan)

City: Dhaka | **Country:** Bangladesh

-Identified and resolved automatic winder challenges. Instructed customers in routine maintenance and operating equipment. Created and updated policies and procedures. Produce and amend training manual. Enforced safety guidelines for clients and staff.

- Daily oversight of the installation, maintenance, renovations, and upgrades for ~2K automatic winders (Machine)
- · Managed 150 customer accounts including training, maintenance, operations and Trouble shooting.
- Raised overall customer satisfaction ensuring reputation for fast, efficient service and maintenance.
- Submit working report and progress report to Japan and all related parson including customer.

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

[01/08/2023 - Current] BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY)

CENTRIA UNIVERSITY OF APPLIED SCIENCES https://net.centria.fi/

City: Pietarsaari | Country: Finland | Level in EQF: EQF level 6

[01/03/2009 - 30/08/2013] BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (Electrical and Electronics Engineering)

Atish Dipankar University of Science and Technology https://www.adust.edu.bd

City: Dhaka | Country: Bangladesh | Level in EQF: EQF level 6